STEVEN ADAM

s.adam1@live.com O7875525184 Web address!!!! www.linkedin.com/in/steven-adam1 https://github.com/SadamTest O



PROFILE

A highly experienced ISTQB certified Test Analyst with over 10 years' software testing experience. An excellent communicator, mentor and team player; capable of leading assigned projects from test plan to completion. Currently looking for further opportunities to develop skills in automation testing.



EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior System Tester | British Car Auctions

Oct 2022 - Present

System testing of Microsoft enterprise resource planning (ERP) systems. Duties and achievements include:

- Lead tester for major Dynamics NAV cumulative updates (CU17 to CU67) across 8
 European countries
- Understanding and testing complex Microsoft partner customisations (The NAV People, Prodware, Arquiconsult etc.)
- Implemented test automation (Selenium, C#) within the Finance & HR Applications team

Test Analyst | Phoenix Medical Supplies

May 2015 - Oct 2022

System testing of pharmacy, warehouse management and customer service systems.

- Lead tester for the transformation of Rowlands Pharmacy applications; taking a
 fundamental role in the redesigned and successful implementation of financial
 reconciliation, resource planning, compliance reporting and core business data systems
 onto a modern Azure .NET platform
- Involved in key integration testing for the company's high profile warehouse automation system 'MediPAC'
- Part of the team responsible for delivering software for the setup and management of the innovative 'PilPouch' warehouse
- Heavily involved in a major in-house wholesale legacy system upgrade allowing for the setup of a new warehouse with a NHS Dispensing Appliances Contract (DAC)
- Reporting over 500 genuine defects per year for the past 3 years running
- Consistent 5 star rated management of UAT by business super users
- Trained and supported several long serving colleagues in both testing and business practices

Test Analyst (UAT) | Home Retail Group (Argos)

May 2012 – May 2015

UAT of software utilised by customers, financial services, contact centers and stores.

- Principle tester for the successful integration of Argos card applications with third party credit scoring & fraud prevention systems
- Heavily involved in the transition of an out-of-the-box order progression tool into a business critical BAU system
- Part of the first team to conduct testing on the Argos Card mobile application
- Trusted with emergency fixes, sales file testing and on the night verification checks
- Proven track record of project delivery



EDUCATION & TRAINING

Continuous Testing Foundation (CTF) Certification | DevOps Institute - 2021

Intermediate Certificate in Software Testing | BCS - 2017

ISTQB Foundation Level | QA - 2013

User Acceptance Testing | Coley Consulting - 2013

BA (Hons) | Lancaster University 2005 - 2008

History – First Class Honors

A levels | Walton High School 2003 - 2005

Business Studies – B, History – B, English Literature – C, General Studies – D

GCSE's | Walton High School 1998 - 2003

11 GCSE's Grade A-C (Inc. Maths and English)



SKILLS

- Knowledge of SDLC Agile/Scrum & Waterfall
- Automation Selenium, Gherkin, Playwright, C#, Java
- Tools Azure DevOps, Jira, Zephyr, HP QC,
 Postman, Fiddler, Confluence, Teams, Trello
- System experience:
 - Microsoft Dynamics 365 Business Central& Dynamics NAV
 - o Bespoke (C#, .NET, Unix, Cobol, Azure)
 - o Warehouse (Buetema, RF, Knapp)
- API's, Microservices & third party integration
- SQL queries
- Storyboarding & requirements analysis
- Creating test deliverables
- Defect management & triage
- UAT process and management
- Second line support (Omnitracker)
- Microsoft Office packages (Microsoft 365)

- Proven home working aptitude
- Ability to communicate effectively with technical and non-technical teams, business stakeholders, third parties and off-shore teams
- Reliable, honest and approachable team player
- Self-organizing and able to prioritize workload
- Able to achieve targets and deadlines
- Willing mentor
- Adaptively embrace emerging tech trends (e.g. ChatGPT, Canva)